## Simon Efremov

Software Engineer

Github: github.com/esemi Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/esemi

esemiko@gmail.com +420 604 872 966 Prague, Czech Republic

#### Summary

Software Engineer with 15+ years experience in product-oriented companies. Can set up the development process or be included on ongoing, from scratch to release. My primary language is Python and comfortable with Rust and Scala. Interested in data scrapping, graphs and investments. Best motivated when see the impact on end users.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineer

Prague, Czech Republic 01/2022 - present

Semrush Inc, Sharing Center & Corporate Access

- o Develop new features and help to plan the team's half-year horizon roadmap.
- o Tech: MongoDB, MySQL, Python, FastAPI, Flask, GRPC, GitLab CI, Pytest, Kubernetes, Helm, GCP.
- Improved the teammates on-boarding process: reviewed documentation and automated manual activities using CI/CD.
- Standardised tasks for integration with other teams: accelerated new integrations.
- o Implemented a new access distribution model for corporate clients: made the user experience of the corporate access tool much simpler for 30% of users.

## Lead Software Engineer

Remote

Gyre TV

10/2021 - 12/2022

- o Participating in defining the product roadmap, decomposing new features into tasks, and solving technical challenges.
- o Tech: PostgreSQL, Python, FastAPI, React, GitHub Actions, Pytest, asyncio.
- Rebuilt the data collection system: 50x growth in user base and streams.
- Moved part of the infrastructure to another hosting provider: reduced hardware expenses by 30%.
- Released the first version of the streaming partnership service: from POC to production-ready service.

### Lead Software Engineer

Semrush Inc, Billing Platform

Prague, Czech Republic

05/2020 - 12/2021

- o Tracked the tech goal roadmap, collected requirements for the new subscription system, designed and implement it.
- o Tech: PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Python, PHP, FastAPI, Flask, GitLab CI, Pytest, Kubernetes, Helm, GCP.
- Supported a sales model change: designed and implemented the POC of the new SaaS subscription system.
- Migrated the team's services to the cloud infrastructure: reduced infrastructure expenses by 60%.
- Supported company expansion: conducted 100+ interviews with candidates for my own and other teams.

## Software Engineer

St. Petersburg, Russia

Various companies, details of previous experience available on request.

07/2008 - 05/2020

## Projects

- Crypto trading robot (Cryptocurrency, Trading): Trading strategy backtesting utility and trading robot for Binance and ByBit cryptocurrency exchanges. Tech: Python, Redis. (Sep '23)
- Online game bot (Gaming, Automation): Fully automatic game bot for MMORPG. Tech: Python, Telethon. (May '23)
- Wellness Mobile App (Mobile, NLP): Dream analysis application uses natural language processing. Tech: Python, PostgreSQL, FastAPI, nltp, Firebase. (September '22)
- Tax calculator tool (Investing, Taxes, CLI tools, link): Used by Czech residents for tax reporting based on Interactive Brokers LLC report. Tech: Python, pandas. (May '22)
- Investment portfolio management tool (Investing, CLI tools): Portfolio management software based on reports from five brokerages. Tech: Scala, Javascript, XPath. (April '21)
- Dating face search tool (Crawlers, Search Engine, Face Detection, Face Recognition): An automatic analytical system to find Tinder® users by facial image search. Tech: Python, Redis, AWS, OpenCV, Scikit, FFmpeg, (March '19)
- Adult movie data analysis (Crawlers, Visualisation, Graph Theory, Web Services, link): An interactive graph of pornhub.com clips based on backlinks. Tech: Python, Javascript, lxml, Puppeteer, MongoDB, Sigma.js, Gephi. (July '18)
- Music clustering (Crawlers, Music, Research, link): A huge visualisation of the overlap of music styles on Yandex Music (Spotify-like service). Tech: Python, Selenium, lxml, igraph (November '17)

#### EDUCATION

# University of Information Technologies, Mechanic and Optics

St. Petersburg, Russia 09/2006 - 05/2012

Specialist Degree in Information Systems and Technology (Master's equivalent)

#### SKILLS

• Languages: Python, SQL, PHP

• Tools: FastAPI, Starlette, Flask, Sanic, aiogram, telethon, SQLAlchemy, Selenium, Pytest, Poetry, asyncio

• Data: PostgreSQL, Redis, MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4j

• Infrastructure: Kubernetes, Helm, Docker, GCP, GitLab CI/CD, GitHub Actions, Grafana, Splunk